SUROJIT MANNA

KOLKATA, INDIA 700159

9073506555

frontenddevsuro@gmail.com

- SUMMARY

Creative and analytical, I bring background in design and problem-solving to front-end development. Skilled in effective communication and collaboration, I excel at transforming ideas into user-friendly digital experiences. My knack for learning new technologies quickly and enthusiasm for continuous improvement ensure I can contribute meaningfully to any team.

EXPERIENCE -

FREELANCER

Kolkata, India

Front End Developer

01/2021 to Current

- Utilized responsive web design to ensure optimal device compatibility
- Boosted site traffic through optimized web content
- Designed and developed responsive websites using modern web technologies
- Actively involved in daily stand-ups and retrospective meetings
- Reviewed and improved website backend efficiency
- Worked on wireframes and prototypes alongside designers to enhance UI
- Enhanced search engine rankings by optimizing web content

TUTORIAL SOLUTION

Kolkata, India

Teacher

Educated BCA, BSC, BTECH students on C++, Java, Python
Educated Higher School students in Java programming

PARTY PROPZ

Kolkata, India

Front End Developer

07/2018 to 08/2020

08/2020 to 09/2024

- Designed websites to be fully functional across a range of device types
- Increased site visibility and drove higher traffic through improved SEO practices
- Crafted seamless user experiences through effective front-end design.
- Refined coding infrastructure, leading to notable efficiency gains

GODARA CONSTRUCTION CO

Silchar, India

Office Manager

03/2017 to 05/2018

- Developed office guidelines to boost operational efficiencies
- Ensured seamless operation by overseeing timely equipment maintenance
- Enhanced efficiency by integrating advanced technologies

SKILLS

- HTML5 expertise
- JavaScript
- Css3
- Sass
- Material UI
- Bootstrap
- Git / GitHub
- Node.is
- React.is
- Redux
- Motion
- MongoDB

- SQL
- Next.Js
- Mobile-First web development
- APIs integration
- User experience design
- Search engine optimization
- Agile methodologies
- WordPress
- jquery
- Tally Basic
- Microsoft Office

EDUCATION -

Sikkim Manipal University, Gangtok, IN-SK

- Coursework in Full Stack Development.
- Coursework in Data Science

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Calcutta, Kolkata, IN-WB

• Dissertation in Computer Science

	LANGUAGES -	
English:	C2 Hindi :	C1
Proficient	Advanced	
Bengali:	C2	
Proficient		
	CERTIFICATIONS —	
Google AI-Powered ShoModern JavaScript from	neworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4 by The Hong Kong Universit	y of Science and
	HOBBIES AND INTERESTS	
Playing GuitarLego BuildingFitness		
	PERSONAL INFORMATION	
Date of birth: 08/11/1995	Nationality: Indian	

2017

- Build Multiple Ecommerce Website for Client zyozi.com, partypropz.com
- Build Multiple Service Based Website for Client patrarepair.com, ayacenter.in, webrefactor.com

- PROJECTS

Gender: Male

- Build Websites for NGO gourisevapeeth.org
- Personal Portfolio surojit.xyz

Marital status: Unmarried